(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-30T04:41:02.296188",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
始まりはきっと 一つの願い
The beginning is surely a single wish,
それを抱いて 私たちは
holding that close, we...
生まれた孤独な夜空
were born in the lonely night sky,
震える指で 点と点を繋げよう
connecting dots with trembling fingers.
一次元では 寂しすぎるから
One dimension is too lonely,
私たちは 広がりを求めた
so we sought expansion.
では線となり 線は立体となり そこに距離が生まれたけれど
Then it became a line, and distance was born, but...
三次元では ちょっと遠すぎるから
Three dimensions are a bit too far,
私たちは 平面に求めた
so we sought a flat plane.
点は線となり 線は星座となり この夜空を繋ぐよ
Dots become constellations, connecting this night sky.
自分らしくいられる場所を 気づけばずっと探していた
Before I knew it, I was always searching for a place to belong.
煌めく星を 窓の鉄格子の上 この見晴らしを 目印に
With sparkling stars and this view as our landmark,
あぶない君がいつもそこにいたから 嬉しくて続けてんだ
Because you were always there, I'm glad I kept going.
今日まで忘れないでね 僕らの星座は 君がいたから生まれた
Our constellation was born because you were there.
たとえ君がいつの時を生きていても 何かを好きになる気持ち
The feeling of loving something, no matter the era...
大切に歌い続けてね 僕らの星座は 君がいるから生まれた
Continue to sing it preciously, born because you are here.
夜空に輝き 明日へと繋がる
Shining in the night sky, connecting toward tomorrow.
未来を目指して 共にゆこう
Aiming for the future, let's go together.
これは僕らのキセキ。僕とキミと、大切なお子の、この王国で過ごす、かけがえのない日々を綴る僕たちの物語。
This is our miracle. Our story of irreplaceable days.
僕の居る場所はどこにあるの?
Where is the place where I belong?
誰かに必要とされたかった
I wanted to be needed by someone.
夢や希望も捨てきれないけど
I can't completely throw away my dreams and hopes,
なんとなく今を生きている
yet somehow I just live through the present.
Somehow, I live through the present.
どれだけ叫んでも
No matter how much I shout,
この声は君には届かない
this voice doesn't reach you.
どれだけ叫んでも
No matter how much I shout,
この声は君には届かない
this voice doesn't reach you.
金木犀の匂いがした
The scent of osmanthus filled the air.
明日のことも忘れたくなった
I wanted to forget even about tomorrow.
いっそ逃げてしまおうかな
Maybe I should just run away after all.
僕は悲劇の主人公だ
I am the protagonist of a tragedy.
やさしいヒトで居たいなって
Wishing I could remain a gentle person,
でもそんな思いも偽善だ
but even that feeling is just hypocrisy.
誰も幸せにできないの
I can't make anyone happy;
都合良いね、涙が出るの
how convenient, tears start to well up.
Convenient, isn't it? Tears are falling.
どれだけ歌っても
No matter how much I sing,
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
どれだけ歌っても
No matter how much I sing,
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
息が苦しくなる
Breathing becomes painful.
この歌もいつしか終わりが来る
This song too will eventually end.
息が苦しくなる
Breathing becomes painful.
この地球もいつしか終わりが来る
This planet too will eventually end.
金木犀の匂いをまた
I smelled the osmanthus flowers again
思い出した
and remembered.
気付けば…
Before I knew it...
駆けだしていた…
I was running...
揺れ動く 心のままに…
following my swaying heart...
遠ざかる… 白い壁…
Growing distant... the white wall...
一度も… 振り返らずに…
Without looking back even once...
《生命》が… 消え行く季節の…
In the season where life fades away...
胸を刺す… 気配の中で…
Amidst the piercing premonition in my chest...
迫り来る… 暗い闇… 二度と… 明けないような気がして…
Darkness closing in... feeling like it will never dawn again...
転がり落ちそうな心… 必死に抱き止めていた…
Desperately holding onto my tumbling heart...
星空へと続く長い坂道は 永遠にも… 思えたから…
The long slope leading to the starry sky felt like eternity...
咲く花や… 散りぬるを… 神代の《時代》より繰り返す…
Flowers bloom and scatter, repeating since ancient times...
私はそれを… 美しいとは… 思ったことがない…
I have never thought of that as beautiful...
久方の… 春の陽を… 仮初めの影が奪い合う…
Fleeting shadows vie for the long-awaited spring sunlight...
その営みを… 美しいとは… 思ったことがない…
I have never thought of that endeavor as beautiful...
諦めながら… 生きてた… 何も望まないように… それでも…
Living while giving up... hoping for nothing... even so...
手放せなかった… 最後の願いを… 握りしめて駆け上がる…
I couldn't let go... clutching my final wish as I ran upward...
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
鷹嶺ルイ
Takane Lui
フワワ・アビスガード / モココ・アビスガード
Fuwawa Abyssgard / Mococo Abyssgard
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
曇天Halloween Night!
Donten Halloween Night!
我武者者に生きるお前が笑われて
Mocked for living so recklessly,
楽に生きる奴らが得をする世界で 我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
in a world where those who live easily reap rewards—I alone will not laugh at you!
皆が指さし笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh!
ああ人は滅んでゆく 綻んでゆく 私を妬み合い富を奪い合い
Ah, humans perish, unravelling, envying each other and fighting over wealth,
ああ人は滅んでゆく 綻んでゆく
Ah, humans perish, unravelling.
その果てに見えた海は 地獄だろうか？それとも地獄だろうか？
Is the sea seen at the end hell? Or is it hell?
我武者者に生きるお前が笑われて 楽に生きる奴らが得をする世界で 我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
Mocked for living so recklessly, in a world where those who live easily reap rewards—I alone will not laugh at you!
皆が指差して笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
You, who live honestly, are disparaged,
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live by lies prosper.
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
Only I will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない！
Even if time ticks away and we forget, I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I will never forget!
身を粉にして働いても
Even if I work myself to the bone,
感謝されないことも……（シバシバ）
Even things that go unthanked... (Blinking)
「自己犠牲」を受け入れても限界がもうやってくるから
Even if you accept "self-sacrifice," your limit is already approaching,
自分を大事に愛せばいい
So you should cherish and love yourself.
それは他人を愛すること
That is to love others as well.
ああ 人は滅んでゆく 絶えてゆく
Ah, people perish, they fade away,
元に戻ってゆく
Returning to what they were before.
ああ 人は蘇ってゆく 救われてゆく
Ah, people revive, they are saved,
君に逢えたから…… 君を愛したから
Because I met you... Because I loved you,
君が戦うなら…… 僕も戦うから……
If you will fight... I will fight too...
我武者らに生きるお前が笑われて
You, who live so recklessly, are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で
In a world where those who live easily reap the rewards.
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
Only I will not laugh at you!
皆が指差して笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
You, who live honestly, are disparaged,
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live by lies prosper.
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
Only I will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない！
Even if time ticks away and we forget, I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I will never forget!
それじゃあ今夜は、この王国のお話をしていこう。
Well then, tonight let's talk about this kingdom.
嘘か真か、ここに記されている本は内容がコロコロと変わってしまう、不思議な本でね。
True or false, the book written here is a mysterious one whose contents change constantly.
さて、今回はどんなお話になっているかな。
Now then, I wonder what kind of story it is this time.
これはあるサーカスの一団が王国へ訪れ、
This is a story of a circus troupe visiting a kingdom,
まだ未熟な座長さんが綺羅びやかなステージに包まれたお話
Where a still inexperienced ringleader was enveloped in a dazzling stage.
ああ…これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング
Ah... this is the dream ending I wished for.
さあ、今日も始まりました〜！ 綺羅びやかな享楽のパレード
Now then, today has begun! A dazzling, hedonistic parade,
常識もここじゃ無関係 踊れ歌え騒け全て忘れて
Where common sense means nothing. Dance, sing, make noise, and forget everything!
細かいことは置いておいて とりあえず身を任せてみな
Leave the trivial details aside and entrust yourself for now!
幸福を少し分けるような饗宴 Show Time!
A banquet that shares a bit of happiness, Show Time!
積もりづく不安や後悔 今だけはちょっと目を背けて
Accumulated anxiety and regrets—just look away for now,
そのままじゃ楽しめないじゃん この場だけは何もかも忘れて！
You won't enjoy yourself like that; forget everything just for now!
幾千の価値観全部 引っ括め楽しませたげる！
I'll scoop up thousands of values and let you enjoy them all!
百鬼夜行もビックリの隊を成している
Forming a troop that would surprise even the Night Parade of One Hundred Demons.
怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け 一目見ればたちまち虜に！？
The comedy imitating the bizarre opens its curtain; one look and you're instantly captivated?!
どんな愛も受け入れてくれる ここだけはあなたの理想郷
Accepting any kind of love, this place alone is your utopia.
「もう間もなく主役の登場、一時でも目を離さないで！」
"The protagonist's appearance is almost here, don't take your eyes off for a second!"
眩いほどのステージが始まる。
A dazzling stage begins.
華々しいスポットライトの中 目を奪うような妙技の数々
Amidst the brilliant spotlights, dazzling feats that steal your gaze,
この空間が世界で一番 “娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
This space is most worthy of the name "entertainment" in the whole world!
割ればかりの歓声と拍手で ショーは終わっていく
Amidst thunderous cheers and applause, the show comes to an end.
まあ、これはあくまで理想の話なんですが^^;
Well, this is just an ideal story, after all...
さて、今日も始めましょう…
Now then, let's begin today as well...
あ〜、またやっちゃった
Ah, I messed up again.
実際はご覧の通り、まだまだ未熟な見習いなんです；；
In reality, as you can see, I'm still just a clumsy apprentice;;
先人に憧れて、私も！と飛び込んだものの
Though I admired my predecessors and leaped in saying, "Me too!"
現実人はそんな簡単にうまくいかないな
Reality doesn't go so easily as planned.
もう一回！
Once more!
「怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け 一目見ればたちまち虜に！？」
"A bizarre-mimicking comedy raises its curtain—captivated at first sight!?"
え？既にそれさっき見た？なら、飽き性なあなたにも【朗報】
Huh? You already saw that earlier? Then I have good news for you impatient folks!
Q.ちょっと前の模倣をするだけ？
Q. Just mimicking what was right before?
A.繰り返しじゃつまらない！だから、ここから先は趣向を変えてみよう！
A. Repetition is boring! So from here on out, let's change things up!
ドタバタなサーカスの行方は
Where is this slapstick circus headed?
誰にも自分すらも分からない！？私を選んだ君だけでも楽しんでってよ〜〜！！！
Not even to anyone, not even to myself!? Enjoy it even if you chose me~~~!!!
いつかの日か皆と楽しめるショーがしたいんだよな
I want to put on a show that everyone can enjoy one day.
だからこそ、こんなとこで挫けるわけがかな〜い！
That's precisely why I won't give up in a place like this~!
言葉なんかじゃ言い表せない あの感動を私もいつか…
That emotion which cannot be expressed in words... I too, someday...
とても偉大なこのステージに見合っているか分からないけれど
Though I don't know if I measure up to this immensely great stage,
観客全て、私の色で染め尽くしてやろう！
I'll dye every single spectator completely in my colors!
手始めに、今、眼の前の君たちからいくよ〜〜！！！
To start with, I'm going with you guys right in front of me~~~!!!
創造しよう華々しいスポットライトの中目を奪うような妙技の数々
Let's create dazzling feats that steal your gaze amid the brilliant spotlight.
この空間が世界で一番“娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
This space is most worthy of the name "entertainment" in the world!
割ればかりの歓声と拍手でショーが終わっていく
The show ends amidst resounding cheers and applause.
ああ…これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング。
Ah... this is the dream ending I wished for.
これは花のお姫様がこの王国へいらっしゃった時のお話
This is the story of when the princess of the flower kingdom came to this kingdom.
まだみんな彼女の事を知らない頃だったので国民の大半は、アホの子なんて言ってたけど、
Since it was a time when not everyone knew about her yet, most citizens called her an idiot, but
ととっても心優しくそして気さくで頼りになるお姫様だったんだよ
She was a very kind, friendly, and reliable princess.
なんてったって、みこはお姫様なのだから！
After all, Miko is a princess!
女神！聖女！叡智！聡明！慈愛！博愛！ですわ！
Goddess! Saint! Wisdom! Brilliance! Affection! Universal love! That's right!
あたしなんてたって お姫様 この人生におけるヒロイン
No matter what, I am a princess, the heroine of this life—
ですわーー！
that's right~~!
一生そのままイージーモード？って思ったら勝手にどうぞ？
"An easy mode life forever?" If you think that, go ahead!
世間はいつも向かい風
Society is always a headwind.
有象無象ばっかりでホント人間不信になっちゃう
With nothing but riffraff, it honestly makes me lose faith in humanity.
気づいたのこの世界に１ミリも涙もないこと
I realized there isn't a single millimeter of tears in this world.
あれもダメこれもダメそれもダメどれもダメ現実世知辛い
"That's no good, this is no good..." — reality is harsh!
改変だ…全部改変ですわ…！
Modification... Total modification, that is...!
あたしなんてたって お姫様 この人生におけるヒロイン 悲しいシナリオも
No matter what, I am a princess, the heroine of this life—even sad scenarios,
全部全部書き換えちゃうの
I'll rewrite them all completely!
だってだって お姫様 自分の物語くらいは キラキラ楽しまなくちゃ ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Because after all, I'm a princess! I've gotta enjoy my own story glittering and sparkling!
今みてなさい！運命なんて 改変して差し上げますわ！
Now watch me! I will modify even fate for you!
だれ？だれ？だれ？だれ？だれ？裏で糸を引いてるのはだれ？
Who? Who? Who? Who? Who is pulling the strings behind the scenes?
操り人形だなんて ごめんわまったっく
"A marionette" — absolutely not, spare me!
上品な顔をしてても苦労まみれあの人かも
Even with a refined face, that person might be full of hardships.
まずはあたしが強くならなきゃ 未来は変わらない
First, I have to become strong, or the future won't change.
自分改革ですわ…！
Self-reform, that is...!
そうよなんてたって お姫様 あたしこそ最高権力者
That's right, no matter what, I am a princess, I am the supreme authority!
ショーの全ての主導権はあたしにあるわ
All initiative of the show belongs to me.
だってだって お姫様 自分で決めたことくらいは
Because after all, I'm a princess! At least what I've decided for myself...
おおいちょ待い待ち合わせ
Wait, hold on, waiting for you!
喰らえドーピング＆ドーピング・ラヴ
Eat this, Doping & Doping Love!
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
That's right! That's right! That's right!
女神！聖女！叡智！聡明！慈愛！博愛！
Goddess! Saint! Wisdom! Intelligence! Compassion! Philanthropy!
ですわ！
That's right!
今日も軽くステップでする
Taking light steps today too,
運命の歯車が踊り出す
the gears of fate begin to dance.
顔を上げたその時 ほら世界が恋する
The moment you lift your face, look, the world falls in love.
あたしハッピーエンドプリンセス この人生におけるヒロイン
I'm the happy end princess, the heroine of this life.
すったもんだアルチミも全部全部愛してみせるの
All the fuss and alchemy, I'll show you I can love it all.
ハッピーエンドプリンセス 自分の物語くらいはキラキラ楽しまなきゃ
Happy end princess, at least in your own story, you've got to enjoy it sparklingly!
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
That's right! That's right! That's right!
全力で生き抜かなきゃ ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
You gotta survive with all your might! That's right! That's right! That's right!
今に見てなさい！運命なんて改変して差し上げますわ！
Just you wait! I'll go ahead and alter your fate!
女神！聖女！叡智！聡明！慈愛！博愛！ですわ！
Goddess! Saint! Wisdom! Intelligence! Compassion! Philanthropy! Indeed!
王国で一躍有名になった小説の1つじゃないか
Isn't this one of the novels that suddenly became famous in the kingdom?
ある女子学生探偵と推理作家の先生が織りなす楽しい…え？
A fun tale woven by a female student detective and a mystery writer teacher... Huh?
いやいやこの事件が実際にあったのかまではわからないよ、
No, no, I don't know if this case actually happened,
でも、このシリーズは凄く人気なんですよね
but this series is super popular, you know.
わかりました！犯人はあなたですね！
I got it! The culprit is you!
あ 嵌め込もう ストーリーライン七つの道具は仕掛け
Ah, let's fit the story line, the seven tools are traps.
悪霊にドトされた探偵が また一人姿を消した という
A detective downed by an evil spirit disappeared one more time, they say.
綾なす筋のAlice側 夜見の掃除は江戸川が
The Alice side of the woven plot, Edogawa cleans up the underworld.
神田最弱探偵さん こんなんどーいると思う？
Kanda's weakest detective, what do you think of this?
ナンモンダブして 脳髄の随これ異質なりや
Making a fuss about nothing, are the depths of the brain heterogeneous?
グーとチーであった人 グーとチーで別れましょう 謎解きはこれから
Those who were rock and scissors, let's part ways with rock and scissors, the mystery-solving is from here on!
「犯人はあなたです！」
"The culprit is you!"
列車トリック 八卦トリック 難事件 推理作家の先生さん
Train trick, bagua trick, difficult case, mystery writer teacher!
ハハハ うだらばたらうだらばたら暇がないぜ ああもう
Haha, no time to dawdle and idle, ah jeez,
頭がこんがらがってきたけれど ドトハライドットコム あっちゃっちゃっパリパリEVERYBODYわんこそば
my head's getting all tangled up, but Doto Harai Dot Com, oopsie daisy crispy EVERYBODY wankosoba,
「謎はおやつに入りません」
"Mysteries are not included in snacks."
ドトハライドットコム あっちゃっちゃっどっしりどっしりEVERYBODYアルバイトないないない
Doto Harai Dot Com, oopsie daisy heavy heavy EVERYBODY part-time job no no no!
エトセトラ列車番外からスナギバンダリさん続いてご清聴
From the et cetera train extras, Sunagibandari-san, continued listening,
ホリエント急行車窓の窓 あの回頭たちがまくとう言う
Orient Express train window, those turning heads say makuto.
孤木に二人海の原 舌口暗号無視したろ
Two people on a solitary tree in the open sea, ignoring the tongue-mouth cipher, right?
ABCどこエビスだか レモンドンちゃんと試験
ABC where is Ebisu or something, Remondon proper exam,
甲が乙を隠す そんじゃごさん香織きさんお疲れさん
甲 hides 乙, well then Gosan Kaoriki-san, good job,
死者五人うやってみな 死者五人どこ行った
try counting five dead people, where did five dead people go?
謎解きはまだまだ
The mystery solving is still far from over,
「そして誰もいなくなった？」親指になっておやめになって怪事件
"And Then There Were None?" Become a thumb and stop, mysterious incident,
おさえ揺らす探偵さん ノックスべべガストンべべいかないでアームチェア
Holding and swaying detective-san, Knox baby Gaston baby, don't go armchair,
先生の意地悪は甘い ドトハライドットコム あっちゃっちゃっパリパリEVERYBODYわんこそば
The teacher's teasing is sweet, Doto Harai Dot Com, oopsie daisy crispy EVERYBODY wankosoba,
「常套句は自分で考えなさい」
"Think of clichés yourself."
ドトハライドットコム あっちゃっちゃっどっしりどっしり
Doto Harai Dot Com, oopsie daisy heavy heavy
じゃあちょっと目を閉じて
Now, close your eyes for a moment,
僕の腕に捕まっていてよ
and hold tight to my arm.
君の笑顔 盗む奴から
From the one who'd steal your smile,
君を盗むのさ
I'm going to steal you away.
物語の名前は伏せたまま始めよう
Let's start the story with its title hidden.
連れ去ってと合図をくれたら
Once you give me the signal to take you away,
ここから君を奪って 夜空を抜けて
I'll snatch you from here, passing through the night sky,
宝石みたいな 街を飛び越えて
and fly right over a city like a jewel.
君が想像した事がないくらい
Beyond anything you could ever imagine,
眩しい世界を見せてあげる
I'll show you a dazzling world.
そのまま海を渡って 春風に乗って
Crossing the ocean just like that, riding the spring breeze,
虹を散乱させて 空にばら撒いて
scattering rainbows and sowing them across the sky,
君は今日も明日も君のままでいていいんだよ
you can stay just as you are, today and tomorrow.
君がいれば僕に不可能なんかない
With you here, nothing is impossible for me.
もう行かないとって
Saying we have to go now,
ガラスの靴で 月にでも戻るの？
will you return to the moon in glass slippers?
君がどう否定したって 素敵なままでだよ
No matter how you deny it, you remain wonderful.
君と出逢えた僕と 出逢えなかった先の僕を 比べて論文にしたいところだけど
I'd love to write a paper comparing the me who met you
君の細胞全体の 尊さはきっと伝えられやしないから
and the me who wouldn't have, but I could never fully convey
君自身を僕が証明するよ
the preciousness of every single cell in you.
ここから君を奪って 夜空を抜けて
I'll snatch you from here, passing through the night sky,
宝石みたいな街を飛び越えて
and fly right over a city like a jewel.
君が想像した事がないくらい
Beyond anything you could ever imagine,
眩しい世界を見せてあげる
I'll show you a dazzling world.
そのまま海を渡って 春風に乗って
Crossing the ocean just like that, riding the spring breeze,
虹を散乱させて空にばら撒いて
scattering rainbows and sowing them across the sky,
君は今日も明日も君のままでいていいんだよ
you can stay just as you are, today and tomorrow.
君がいれば僕に不可能なんかない
With you here, nothing is impossible for me.
小さい2人の子供が約束した
Two little children made a promise,
ずっと一緒に笑っていようの約束
a promise to always laugh together.
今もなお、2人の絆は確かなもので
Even now, the bond between the two remains steadfast—
友情と愛情が織りなす素敵な物語
a wonderful story woven by friendship and affection.
あはは…なんでもないことに、妙にツボっちゃう時あるよねっ
Ahaha... Sometimes you just find yourself obsessing over nothing at all, right?
ああ 恋に落ちた舞うら
Ah, my fluttering heart fell in love.
咲き止まないや
It won't stop blooming.
何度も巡って 心をかし
Turning around again and again, playing with my heart.
泣いてばっかだったの
I was always crying,
それがどうだい 今や
but how about that? Now,
腹捩るくらい笑う
I laugh until my stomach hurts.
ずっと一緒に笑う
Laughing together forever.
きみが持ってる 白い花に
To the white flower you hold,
あたし見合わない 悲しくなる
I don't match, and it makes me sad.
無垢な恋とか 正しさとか
Innocent love, righteousness, and such—
誰も教えてくれなかった
nobody ever taught me.
昨日会ったばっかで
We just met yesterday,
今日もどっか会えたら
and if we can meet somewhere today,
なんて思う暮らし 包ましいくらいだよね
living like that—it's almost modest, isn't it?
全部許されたの びっくりしちゃってさ
I was so surprised that everything was forgiven,
涙あふれてたよ
tears overflowed.
もう愛になる花歌 透き通った空に
A flower song turning into love, in the clear sky,
手を繋いでった 夢のしるし
the proof of a dream where we held hands.
どんな前世だってさ
No matter what past life it was,
忘れたっていいんだ きみと笑えるなら
it's fine to forget it, as long as I can laugh with you.
心が触れるたび 綺麗な音鳴る
Every time our hearts touch, a beautiful sound rings out.
目と目が合ってくすぐったいね
Our eyes meet, and it feels ticklish.
なんでもないこと 妙にツボるね
Finding humor in nothing at all is so funny.
全部教えてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for teaching me everything.
きみが持ってる白い花を あたしの紅色と合わせたら
To the white flower you hold, if I match it with my crimson color,
霜が溶けては 雲が行く
the frost will melt and clouds will drift away,
もう寒くないよ
and it won't be cold anymore.
ああ 恋に落ちた舞うら
Ah, my fluttering heart fell in love.
咲き止まないや
It won't stop blooming.
何度も巡って 心をかし
Turning around again and again, playing with my heart.
泣いてばっかだったの
I was always crying,
それがどうだい 今や
but how about that? Now,
腹捩るくらい笑う
I laugh until my stomach hurts.
ずっと一緒に笑って
Laughing together forever,
心をかし
playing with my heart.
ずっと一緒に笑う 最後の日を笑う
Laughing together forever, laughing on our final day.
これは、遠い遠い 名も知らぬ世界で
This is a story from a distant, unknown world...
死の呪いがかけられた少女のお話
A story of a girl cursed with death.
遠い遠い時の果て そこに住まう人達は
At the far end of time, the people living there
皆永遠の命をもつ 世界での話
all possess eternal life in this world's story.
赤い実の成る木の下 生まれながらに
Beneath the tree of red fruit, born with...
死の呪いがかけられた 少女の話
a story of a girl cursed with death.
色付いた街外れ 青く光る琥珀
On the colorful outskirts of town, amber glows blue.
赤い実のお菓子屋
A confectionary shop of red fruit.
ちょっぴり寒くなった 今日は妙に誇らしげ
Getting a bit colder today, strangely proud.
自信作を売りゆく
Going to sell my masterpiece.
待ってて 今度こそ 美味しいんだから
Wait for it, because this time it's delicious!
時計塔の見える市 珍しく賑やかね
The city with the clock tower is unusually lively.
物憂げ街の隅 ひとり
Alone in the corner of a dreary town.
赤い実のパイですが 自信作なの
It's a red fruit pie, but it's my masterpiece!
そんなの ひとつも売れないさ
Not a single one of those will sell.
少女を見て蔑む人達 みんなと何処も変わらないのに
People looking down at the girl, even though she's no different from anyone...
美味しくできたのに
Even though it was made deliciously.
今日も声は届かないのね まるで透明になったみたいだわ
Today too, my voice doesn't reach, as if I've become transparent.
そして 誰もが知らぬ振りをした
And everyone pretended not to know.
何故なら少女は呪われているから
Because the girl is cursed.
死んだ世界でただ一人生きていた 少女の話
A story of a girl who lived all alone in a dead world.
夜衣べでアレンジパイとニコリスマイル引っ下げ
With a night robe, arranged pie, and a smiling face ready,
少女はまだ諦めない
the girl still hasn't given up.
時計塔の針も空を指して お腹も鳴るそんな時
When the clock tower's hands point to the sky and my stomach rumbles,
ふと後ろから人が少女を押す 甘い籠は落ちる
suddenly someone pushes the girl from behind, and the sweet basket falls.
お菓子を踏み行く人達 平気顔顔してさ
People stepping on the sweets with nonchalant faces,
惨めに拾い集める ふともうひとりの手が
miserably gathering them up, when suddenly another hand...
どろどろのパイを口に入れ 「おいしいね」
puts the muddy pie into their mouth and says, "Delicious."
その声で心はあふれた
With that voice, my heart overflowed.
まるで輪郭を描いたみたいだわ
As if tracing an outline.
そして彼は手を差し出した
And then he reached out his hand.
何故なら少女に呪われているから
Because the girl is cursed.
死んだ世界でただふたり生きていた 遠い物語
A distant story of two people living in a dead world.
街の人達は哀れむ 赤い実を食べて呪われた者
People in the town pity those cursed by eating the red fruit,
永遠に生きられずに死ぬのさ 鳴呼呼なんて可哀想な話
dying without living forever. Ah, what a pitiful story.
ふたりは笑う それでも笑う
The two of them smile, even so, they smile.
La La La とっても素敵な呪いだね
La La La, what a truly wonderful curse.
例え明日死んでも 『今』が確かで大切な話になるから
Even if we die tomorrow, because 'now' becomes a certain and precious story.
もう声は届かないのね
My voice no longer reaches,
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
as if I've become transparent.
そして 誰もが知らぬ振りをした
And everyone pretended not to know.
何故なら世界が呪われているから
Because the world is cursed.
『永遠』の呪いは解かれていた
The curse of 'eternity' had been lifted.
まるでふたりの方が狂ったみたいだろう
As if the two of them were the ones who went mad.
そして いつか笑うように眠る
And sleeping so she'll someday smile again,
何故ならふたりは放たれているから
because the two of them have been set free.
死んだ世界で唯ふたりだけが幸せだった
In a dead world, only the two of them were happy.
さて、今日はこれくらいにしておきましょう、
Now then, let's call it a day here.
…そろそろ時間になりましたし
...It's almost time, after all.
…え？どこへ向かうのかって？
...Eh? Where are we heading, you ask?
今日は何の日かご存知ないのですか？
Do you not know what day today is?
今日は、この王国の地下深くにある冥界でのハロウィンパーティですよ！
Today is a Halloween party in the underworld deep beneath this kingdom!
死者と生者が楽しむ年に一度のお祭りです。
It's a once-a-year festival where the dead and living enjoy themselves.
さぁ、一緒に向かいましょう、
Now then, let's head there together.
でも、気を付けて。パーティとはいえ、死者が住まう冥界です。
But be careful. Party or not, it's the underworld where the dead reside.
誰かの思念や死者達によって奇妙な事が起こるかもしれません、
Strange things might happen due to someone's thoughts or the dead,
でも、決してそちらに耳を傾すぎてはいけませんよ…
but you must never lean your ears too close to them...
それでは、参りましょう
Well then, let's be on our way.
蒼炎
[Souen]
誰かが言いました
Someone said:
激しく燃えるものほど
"The more intensely something burns,
煌めく引き換えに その身をすぐ焦がしきると
in exchange for its brilliance, it soon burns itself out entirely."
数ある燭台に
Upon the numerous candlesticks,
お好きな火を灯しましょう
let's light whichever fire you please.
期待と裏腹に 燃ればお生憎様
Contrary to expectations, if it burns, too bad for you—
ランランランラン
La, la, la, la,
右手には錆びた時計
a rusted clock in the right hand,
ランランランラン
la, la, la, la,
左には油の筒
a cylinder of oil in the left,
ランランランラン
la, la, la, la,
猟のドレスを着飾って さぁ
dressed up in a hunting dress, now then!
激しく 儚く
Intensely and fleetingly,
青く燃える花びら
petals burning a pale blue,
瞬き ゆらめく
flickering and shimmering,
生を彩り照らせ
brighten and color our lives
いずれ尽き果てる未来へと
toward a future that will eventually burn out.
ゆりかごの目の前で
Right before the cradle,
遠く飛び交う銃弾
bullets fly back and forth in the distance.
指だけ動かせば容易くその火は潰える
Just moving a finger would easily extinguish that flame.
仮初の情熱で焼け爛れた舌では
With a tongue burnt and blistered by feigned passion,
上手に喋ることができないようで
it seems you cannot speak well,
喉もと過ぎても毒を孕ませて
swallowing the poison even past your throat...
気付けば見知らぬ世界に立っていた
Before I realized, I found myself lost in here
何処かも分からず毎日毎日毎日泣いていた
Lost and confused, every day I shed, I shed, I shed, all my tears
なんて暇もなく
Ah, but I couldn't even afford time
ハッピータイム！ おかしな面々が
Happy time! All the odd ones gathering all around
ハッピータイム！ おどけて転がるの
Happy time! Playing games as we stumble to the ground
ハッピータイム！ その馬鹿馬鹿しさに
希望も恐怖もなくなった
Happy time! Where nonsense keeps us entertained
All hopes and fears fade in the crowd
確かそうアタシには
I'm certain there's a task for me
為すべき仕事 愛の棲家
A place I belong, where love feels ever so sweet
パンプキン ヘッドギア
だけどなんだかどうでもいい
A pumpkin mask I wear as gear
But honestly, I found it hard to care
さあ 始まった 夢の夜だ
音楽が響いて鳴りやまない
So now the night of dreams is here forever
The music echoes through, never fading away
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
アメイジング ハッピー ハロウィンナイト
Come scream with us, let's live in this delight
Amazing happy Halloween night
ジャック いたずら 無礼講だ
真面目に生きても割に合わない
Jack is scheming, tricks are being unleashed
Playing it lightly, we're running wild, with no serious leash
なんでもあるさ何故って今日は
アメイジング ハッピー ハロウィンナイト
The rules are shattered just for today
Cause it's an amazing happy Halloween night
あちらの世界に引きずり込まれないうちに早く会場へ向かわないといけませんね。
Before I realized, I found myself lost in here...
気を付けてついてきてくださいね、
Take care and follow me closely, okay?
あまり深入りすると、おっと…
If you pry too much... oops.
そうそう、知らないほうがきっと懸命ですよ。
That's right, it's best if you don't know anything.
なんだかすっごく心地が良いよね。
For some reason, it feels so good...
気付けば見知らぬ世界に立っていた
Before I realized, I found myself lost in here
何処かも分からず毎日毎日毎日泣いていた
Lost and confused, every day I shed, every single day I cried
なんて暇もなく
Ah, but I couldn't even afford time
ハッピータイム！ おかしな面々が
Happy time! All the odd ones gathering all around
ハッピータイム！ おどけて転がるの
Happy time! Playing games as we stumble to the ground
ハッピータイム！ その馬鹿馬鹿しさに
希望も恐怖もなくなった
Happy time! Where nonsense keeps us entertained
All hopes and fears fade in the crowd
確かそうアタシには
I'm certain there's a task for me
為すべき仕事 愛の棲家
パンプキン ヘッドギア
A place I belong, where love feels ever so sweet
A pumpkin mask I wear as gear
だけどなんだかどうでもいい
さあ始まった夢の夜だ
But honestly, I found it hard to care
So now the night of dreams is here forever
音楽が響いて鳴りやまない
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
The music echoes through, never fading away
Come scream with us, let's live in this delight
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
ジャックいたずら無礼講だ
Amazing happy Halloween night
Jack is scheming, tricks are being unleashed
真面目に生きても割に合わない
なんでもあるさ何故って今日は
Playing it lightly, we're running wild, with no serious leash
The rules are shattered just for today
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
消えちゃった！消えちゃった！
Cause it's an amazing happy Halloween night
It's all lost! It's all lost!
出口はないんだってそう永遠に
消えちゃった！消えちゃった！
There's no escape, that is right, forever
It's all lost! It's all lost!
思想 ルール 倫理 関係ない
アメイジング ハッピー ハロウィンナイト
The idea, rules, and morals won't apply
Amazing happy Halloween night
「私はロボットではありません」に
無心でチェックし解答するけれど本当にそうかな
"I am not a robot," I look and respond automatically
But inside, I wonder if it's all real
ハッピーライフ！ とりま音に乗せて
Happy life! For a second, I'm moving to the song
ハッピーライフ！ デタラメに踊るの
Happy life! I dance randomly without a plan
ハッピーライフ！ その繰り返しの中 懐疑心も失った
Happy life! Going on and on and endlessly
My doubts have just left far away
意志のない様まるで
ロボトミーした電気羊
Now it seems like, it don't have a will
Like a robotic sheep without a mind, to speak
ナイトメア NPC
だけどなんだか心地がいい
A figure, an NPC
But somehow, it brings me joyfulness!
おっと音声が乱れました
お気になさらずに皆様皆様
Oh, the audio just got disrupted
Please don't put too much thought into it, everyone
そんなお口は縫い合わせて
アメイジング ハッピー ハロウィンナイト
Just keep your mouths sewn shut so you can never speak
Amazing happy Halloween night
良い子の口にはチョコとキャンディ
歯に纏わせてっちゃ噛み合わない
Good children get chocolate and all the candy
If you sugarcoat things, they will not fit correctly
気を取直しみんなどうぞ
アメイジング ハッピー ハロウィンナイト
Let's pull ourselves together, everyone
Amazing, happy Halloween night
知っちゃった！知っちゃった！
全部全部理解した
It's all lost! It's all lost!
I just know everything all too well!
だから何も見たくねぇわ
さあ始まった夢の夜だ
I'd rather not look anywhere else
So now the night of dreams is here forever
音楽が響いて鳴りやまない
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
The music echoes through, never fading away
Come scream with us, let's live in this delight
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
ジャックいたずら無礼講だ
Amazing happy Halloween night
Jack is scheming, tricks are being unleashed
真面目に生きても割に合わない
なんでもあるさ何故って今日は
Playing it lightly, we're running wild, with no serious leash
The rules are shattered just for today
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
泣いちゃった！泣いちゃった！
Cause it's an amazing happy Halloween night
I'm crying! I'm crying!
知らない方がきっと懸命ね
このパーティに終わりはない
It's likely best if you are unaware
This celebration goes on forever
ようこそ everyone
Welcome, everyone!
狐の夜だよこの spooky night
It's a fox's night, this spooky night.
腹の底まで浸れ
Immerse yourself to the core,
kick & bass & hats & trumpet
ランタンと swingin' beat
with lanterns and a swingin' beat.
赤い靴で踊り狂えば
If you dance wildly in red shoes,
浮世の憂いも忘れられるでしょ
you can forget the sorrows of this fleeting world, right?
しかもおろちまったじゃ
Moreover, compared to ghosts,
おばけよりも怖い人たち
people are much scarier—
増えすぎちゃってすぐに
multiplying so fast,
1out, 2out, now 3out, knock out!!
1 out, 2 out, now 3 out, knock out!!
コンプライアンスも厳しい世の中ですが
Even in a world with strict compliance,
恐怖のライト受け負います
we'll take charge of the lights of terror!
GIVE ME A CHERRY PIE
それとも may I choke you up?
or may I choke you up?
GIVE ME A FLOWY DRESS
それとも may I stab you to death?
or may I stab you to death?
poison, rope, pumpkin cake,
knife, scissors, whatever you like
knife, scissors, whatever you like—
choose one...
「さあ 選んで」 なんにして
"Now, choose." Whatever you make it—
ドッキリ大成功!
A successful prank!
響くパンパカパンファンファーレで
With a resounding fanfare,
にっこり笑っちゃってはいピース
flash a big smile and strike a peace sign!
あー怖かっただななんて
"Ah, that was so scary," you say,
座り込んで涙目で
squatting down with tearful eyes—
笑う顔みたいな
I want to see that smiling face!
ちっちゃな箱の中の モンスターにおびえるくらいなら
If you're going to cower in fear at monsters inside a tiny box,
いつだってここに置いて
leave them here anytime,
もっとずっと本能的に楽しくなれる今日から
and from today, you can have much more instinctively pure fun!
恐怖と踊っちゃおうぜ
Let's dance with the terror!
躁鬱相転移でキマッてカタルシス
Tripping on manic-depressive phase shifts for catharsis,
もういっちょ感情ジェットコースターでゴキゲンデトックス
and one more emotional roller coaster for a cheerful detox!
満月が暴く邪悪な本性
The full moon exposes our wicked nature;
デタラメに杖振り回し hocus pocus
swinging a wand recklessly—hocus pocus.
劣等感を苗床に育つ呪いを
Do you know the secret to uprooting
摘み取る術を知っているかい?
the curses grown in the seedbed of inferiority?
「迷える憐れな子羊たちよ」
"O wandering, pitiful little lambs,"
「お菓子が欲しいかい? それとも惨めさが欲しいかい?」
"do you want sweets, or do you want misery?"
「永遠に求め続けるの? それならば、ずっと苦しいままだ」
"Will you keep seeking forever? If so, you'll remain in eternal torment."
「恐怖からの解放によって 救い得る救済があるのならば」
"If there is salvation to be gained through release from fear,"
「この目隠しはそのままに さあ」
"leave this blindfold on. Now..."
「イタズラ完了」
"Prank complete."
永遠に断ち切れない 呪いの鎖に囚われ
Trapped in chains of a curse that can never be broken,
朽ちてしまう前に
before you rot away,
脳みそちょっといじるだけであら不思議!
just tweak your brain a little and—how wondrous!
こんなに気持ち良くて 気分爽快
It feels so good, and you feel refreshed.
なんちって ドッキリ大成功!
Just kidding—a successful prank!
響くパンパカパンファンファーレで
With a resounding fanfare,
にっこり笑っちゃってはいポーズ
flash a big smile and strike a pose!
あー辛かっただななんて
"Ah, that was so tough," you whine,
へたり込んで涙目で 笑う顔っていいね
sitting down in tears—a smiling face is so nice.
もう苦しまなくていいよ
You don't have to suffer anymore;
こんなに頑張ったんだから
since you've tried so hard,
躊躇わずこっちにおいで
don't hesitate and come over here.
もっとずっと本能的に気持ちいいだけの ゴールを見せてあげる
I'll show you a destination of purely instinctive pleasure,
極限極まってこそ光るカタルシス
Catharsis shines brightest when extremes are reached,
もういっちょ因果系リセットでタマシイデトックス
and one more karmic reset for a soul detox!
物言わぬくちびるに 息を吹き込んで
Breathing life into silent lips,
今宵あなたは蘇る あの頃の姿で
tonight you awaken in the appearance of those days.
白肌の娘が囀をした。
A pale-skinned maiden chirped softly,
この身貴方に捧げるわ
"I offer this body to you."
白服の医者が囁いた。
A white-clad doctor whispered,
迎えに行くよ
"I'm coming to pick you up."
白肌の娘は朽ち果てた。
The pale-skinned maiden withered away.
世界の誰にも見捨てられ
Abandoned by everyone in the world,
白服の医者は憐れんで
The white-clad doctor pitied her,
誰もいない居場所で眠らせた
And let her sleep in a place where no one else is.
朽ちてなおまだ
Even as she rots, she is
美しい顔で、
Still with a beautiful face,
ふたりしかいない霊廟で、
In a mausoleum where only the two of them are,
医者は恋をした。
The doctor fell in love.
それは永遠の恋か。
Is this an eternal love?
禁断の行為か。
Or a forbidden act?
また逢いたいと願うだけ。
Wishing only to meet again—
それが罪なのでしょうか。
Is that considered a sin?
物言わぬ口唇に生気を吹き込んで、
Breathing life into mute lips,
今宵ふたりは結ばれる。祝福もされずに。
Tonight the two are united, without even a blessing.
腐りかけた眼孔に青い硝子を
In her decaying eye sockets, blue glass
破れかけた腕に絹糸を
On her tearing arms, silk threads
侵された内臓に綿のガーゼを
In her invaded internal organs, cotton gauze
宝石で飾った白いドレスを
A white dress adorned with jewels
朽ちゆくたび取り繕って、
Fixing her up each time she decays,
恋を謳って、また医者は手を染め続けた。
Singing of love, the doctor continued to stain her hands.
やがて暴かれたのは見にくい怪物で、
What was eventually exposed was an ugly monster,
それを作り上げた医者は弁解を叫んだ。
And the doctor who created it cried out in defense.
「これは永遠の恋だ。彼女の願望だ。」
"This is eternal love. It is her desire."
死にゆくと決めたお前が見棄てた女じゃないか。
"Isn't she the woman you abandoned, deciding to die?"
鳴呼……哀しき花嫁。物言えぬままで、
Ah... tragic bride. Remaining unable to speak,
今宵ふたりは裁かれる。彼女を見棄てた人達の正義で。
Tonight the two are judged, by the justice of those who abandoned her.
正しいのはだれ？
Who is right?
さて、ハロウィンパーティもついにフィナーレ！
Now, the Halloween party is finally reaching its finale!
ここでご参加くださった国民の皆様へ、冥界からのお土産のご紹介です。
Here, I'd like to introduce souvenirs from the underworld for all the citizens who participated!
お土産品は全部で4種類。フルセットでご購入いただいた皆様には特典もございます。
There are 4 types of souvenirs in total. There are special bonuses for those who purchase the full set.
ご一緒に詳しく見ていきましょう！
Let's take a closer look together!
まず1つ目。今回の冥界ハロウィンナイトをイメージしたワイドラバーマットです。
First, the first item. A wide rubber mat inspired by this Underworld Halloween Night.
国王様の横には、冥界の女王の姿が、名もナイラというそうです。
Next to the King, the figure of the Underworld Queen—apparently named Naila.
冥界のハロウィンを存分に楽しんでほしいという気持ちを込めた彼女のイメージソングも、このあとお披露目予定なのでお楽しみに！
With the feeling that she wants you to fully enjoy the underworld Halloween, her image song is scheduled to be unveiled soon, so look forward to it!
素敵なイラストはMatcha様に描いていただきました。
The wonderful illustration was drawn by Matcha-sama.
2つ目は、パスポート風FBKINGDOMシール帳です。
Second is the passport-style FBKINGDOM sticker book.
このシール帳には、これからたくさんの思い出を記していきたいですね。
In this sticker book, I'd like to record lots of memories from now on.
王国の奇跡として国民の皆様も今後集めてみてはいかがでしょうか。
As a miracle of the kingdom, why don't you citizens collect them in the future too?
その一歩として、今回のキービジュアルのステッカーを1枚封入しております。
As a first step, we've included one sticker of the main visual.
3つ目は、スコンブファクトリーよりキングフブちゃんぬいぐるみです。
Third is the King Fubuchan plushie from Sukonbu Factory.
こちらは国王自らデザインをしており、とても愛らしいぬいぐるみとなっております。
This was designed by the King herself, making it a very adorable plushie.
前回のボリューム1のぬいぐるみをお持ちの方は、ご一緒に飾ってあげてくださいね。
If you have the Volume 1 plushie from last time, please display them together!
4つ目は、王国リボンチャームです。
Fourth is the Kingdom Ribbon Charm.
こちらは師匠である私の胸元のリボンが再現されております。
This replicates the ribbon on my chest, my master's.
鞄につけ…
Attach it to your bag...
ペンライトにつけるもよしと
Great to attach to penlights,
沢山のデザインのリボンチャームとなっておりますので
as it's designed like a lavish ribbon charm,
皆様のおし活となりにぜひご活用ください！
please make good use of it for your oshi-katsu!
最後は特典のお知らせです。
Lastly, an announcement about bonuses.
フルセットをご購入の方全員にチェキ風ブロマイドカードを1つお付けいたします！
Everyone who purchases the full set will receive one cheki-style bromide card!
複製サインと国王からのメッセージもあるそうですよ。
It includes a duplicated signature and a message from the Queen, apparently.
数量限定バージョンは直筆サイン入りですので皆様お早めに！
The limited quantity version features a hand-signed autograph, so get yours early!
以上、今回のお土産品紹介でした。
That's all for today's souvenir introduction.
この後は冥界の女王様をイメージした楽曲「冥界Halloween Night!」のお披露目です！
Coming up is the premiere of the song 'Meikai Halloween Night!', inspired by the Queen of the Underworld!
楽しまれた後は無事王国へお帰りくださいね。
After you've enjoyed it, make sure to return safely to the kingdom.
それでは！
Well then!
Welcome! さあ踊ろうよ
Welcome! Now let's dance,
This is Halloween Night!
冥界Halloween Night!
Underworld Halloween Night!
冥界を挙げての Party (Party)
A party raising the Underworld (Party),
ルール違反はダメです Warning (Warning)
Breaking the rules is not allowed, Warning (Warning).
説明は一度きり (きり)
The explanation is only once (once),
聞き逃せばあの世行き (冗談です♡)
Miss it and you're bound for the afterlife (Just kidding♡).
(いち！) お菓子を回して
(One!) Pass around the sweets,
(に！) ドレスを着て回って
(Two!) Put on your dress and spin,
(さん！) 生者か死者かは隠す事！
(Three!) Keep whether you're alive or dead a secret!
(よん！) いつだって笑顔で
(Four!) Always with a smile,
(ご！) 最後の最後は無事で帰る事♡
(Five!) The very end means returning safely♡.
独りきりじゃつまらないわ
Being all alone is boring,
この退屈な王室の玉座で
On this boring royal throne,
指を折りずっと待ちわびてた
Counting my fingers, waiting eagerly.
人恋しいとか？
Lonely, you say?
ヤダ！ そんなんじゃないってば！
No way! It's nothing like that!
Let's 冥界Halloween Night!
Let's Underworld Halloween Night!
Dancing! Dancing! 闇夜にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night,
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界Halloween Night!
Rattatta rattatta, Underworld Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! Thrilling and delightful irony,
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム！
Rattatta rattatta, banquet showtime!
(Pe Pe Pa) 恐ろしいや
(Pe Pe Pa) How terrifying,
(Pu Pu Pa) 悪戯や 見い出の身の上のさいも忘れてる
(Pu Pu Pa) Mischief, even forgetting your own fate.
おろろ？ (Pe Pe Pa) 美味しそうな (Pu Pu Pa) 魂じゃん！
Oh my? (Pe Pe Pa) Such delicious (Pu Pu Pa) souls!
Welcome! さあ踊ろうよ
Welcome! Now let's dance,
This is Halloween Night!
響くがくたのチューニング
Tuning of the echoing instrument,
その不協和音さえも Music (Music)
Even that dissonance is Music (Music).
王室のドアが開き
The royal door opens,
拍手喝采が起こる 快感です♡
Applause erupts, it's sheer bliss♡.
(いち！) ロウソクを回して
(One!) Pass around the candles,
(に！) ドレス纏って
(Two!) Put on your dress,
(さん！) 女王の私のお出ましです！
(Three!) It's the grand appearance of me, the Queen!
(よん！) 手を取りあって
(Four!) Holding hands,
(ご！) 今日は無礼講で
(Five!) Today anything goes.
私に見せられちゃったら最後です♡
Once you're shown to me, it's the end♡.
艶やかなステップ くるり舞っては
Twirling in glamorous steps,
百鬼夜行のリズムに揺られて
Swaying to the rhythm of the Night Parade of One Hundred Demons,
この楽しさ 癖になるわ
This fun is becoming a habit.
時間切れとか？
Out of time, you say?
ヤダ！ 全然足りないってば！
No way! It's not nearly enough!
Let's 冥界Halloween Night!
Let's Underworld Halloween Night!
Dancing! Dancing! 人世の奇異なメモリー
Dancing! Dancing! Strange memories of the mortal world,
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界Halloween Night!
Rattatta rattatta, Underworld Halloween Night!
Sweety! Sweety! おぼろに狂えるキャンディー
Sweety! Sweety! Candy that drives you vaguely mad,
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ ああ、もっと頂戴！
Rattatta rattatta, oh, give me more!
泡沫の夢 淡い霧の中溶けて ああ 白い頬を涙が伝った
Melting in the fleeting dream and pale mist, Ah, tears traced down white cheeks.
この娘は誰の為？ 呪文呪いとものすまき 禁断の扉を開けたら
Who is this girl for? Spells and curses rolled up, when I opened the forbidden door.
時間を戻す
Turn back time,
魔法使いちゃおかな？
Shall I use magic?
Dancing! Dancing! 闇夜にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night,
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界Halloween Night!
Rattatta rattatta, Underworld Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! Thrilling and delightful irony,
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム！
Rattatta rattatta, banquet showtime!
(Pe Pe Pa) 恐ろしいや
(Pe Pe Pa) How terrifying,
(Pu Pu Pa) 悪戯や 見い出の身の上のさいも忘れてる
(Pu Pu Pa) Mischief, even forgetting your own fate.
おろろ？ (Pe Pe Pa) 美味しそうな (Pu Pu Pa) 魂じゃん！
Oh my? (Pe Pe Pa) Such delicious (Pu Pu Pa) souls!
Welcome! さあ踊ろうよ
Welcome! Now let's dance,
This is Halloween Night!
ハロウィンパーティー、いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you enjoy the Halloween party?
ちゃんとこちら側の王国に戻ってこられてますか？
Have you made it safely back to our kingdom?
冥界の女王様にお気に召されてしまうと魂を奪われてしまって帰って来られませんからね。
If the queen of the underworld takes a liking to you, she'll steal your soul and you won't be able to come back.
戻ってこられてラッキーでした、なんて。
Aren't you lucky you managed to return?
今日のお話はどうでしたか？楽しかったでしょうか？
How was today's story? Did you enjoy it?
私が特にお気に入りは探偵のお話でした。
My personal favorite was the detective story.
今回お聞かせできてとても嬉しかったです。
I'm so glad I got to share it with you this time.
そうだ、いつかあなたのお話も聞かせてくださいね。
Oh right, please let me hear your story sometime too.
もしかするとあなたのお話も書き記されるかもしれませんよ。
Who knows, your story might even be written down here.
なんと言っても、まか不思議な本ですから。
After all, it's a wondrous and mysterious book.
何が起こるか、司書である私にも分かりません。
Even as the librarian, I have no idea what will happen.
さて、そろそろお時間ですね。
Well, it's almost time.
またお話が聞きたくなりましたら、いつでもこの王国図書館へお越しください。
If you ever want to hear another story again, please come visit this kingdom library anytime.
それでは、さようなら。
Until then, farewell.
ハジマリはきっと一つの願い
Every beginning is surely a single wish,
それを抱いて私たちは生まれた 孤独な夜空 震える指で 点と点をつなげよう
we were born holding it. In the lonely night sky, with trembling fingers, let's connect the dots.
（woh oh woh oh woh oh oh oh）
(Woh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh)
ライブに来た皆さん！準備はできてますか？
Everyone here at the live, are you ready?
セイ！ハロー！行きますよ！
Say! Hello! Here we go!
せい！ ほら どの子も顔上げて
Hey! Look, everyone raise your faces up,
みんなで手を取れば 最強！
if we all hold hands, it's the strongest!
まだまだ道途中 世界を超えよう
Still on the way, let's transcend the world!
ほら 押し押し稼働 止まらない独占欲ですから
Push ahead without stopping, because of our unstoppable desire!
夢を書き換えたら 追いかけ続けよう
Once you rewrite your dream, keep chasing after it!
ともに繋ぐ ファンファーレ GO!
A fanfare connecting us together, GO!
だから君がいつか 自分自身の
So whenever you happen to lose sight
輝きを見失ったときには 思い出してね ぼくらの聖夜は君がいるから輝く
of your own brilliance, remember: our holy night shines because you are here!
眠る星の中 光が君がくれた
Amidst sleeping stars, the light you gave me
スーパーノヴァ起こせ今 何度だって飛び立てる
Supernova, trigger it now, we can take flight no matter how many times!
これは紛れもなく僕らの奇跡 High Five!
This is unquestionably our miracle, High Five!
超えて行けるさ スーパーノヴァ起こせ今 何度だって飛び立てる
We can surpass it, supernova trigger it now, we can take flight no matter how many times!
これは紛れもなく僕らの奇跡 High Five!
This is unquestionably our miracle, High Five!